Taejun Kim

CONTACT Ph.D. Candidate

School of Computing, KAIST

Email: taejun.kim@kaist.ac.kr
URL: https://taejun13.github.io

Kim Byung Ho IT Building (N1) #722 KAIST, 291 Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu Daejeon 34141, Republic of Korea

RESEARCH INTERESTS I'm interested in developing new hands-free VR/AR techniques that can provide enhanced user experiences. Integration of sensing technology (e.g., Eye Tracking) into modern wearable devices must open new possibilities of hands-free interaction. My research focus lies in eye- and head- based interaction, VR/AR interfaces, wearable haptic interfaces. I'm looking forward to presenting my new work on gaze-based menu technique at ACM CHI 2022!

PUBLICATIONS

International Conference and Journal Papers

1. Lattice Menu: A Low-Error Gaze-Based Marking Menu Utilizing Target-Assisted Gaze Gestures on a Lattice of Visual Anchors

Taejun Kim, Auejin Ham, Sunggeun Ahn, Geehyuk Lee CHI 2022: ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

2. Heterogeneous Stroke: Using Unique Vibration Cues to Improve the Wrist-Worn Spatiotemporal Tactile Display

Taejun Kim, Youngbo Aram Shim, Geehyuk Lee

CHI 2021: ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

Domestic Conference Papers

 People Counting and Correction through Combining Existing Contexts in Smart Space Taejun Kim, Hyunju Kim, Dongman Lee Korea Software Congress 2017

 A Task-level Data Stream Segmentation Method based on User Presence in a Smart Space Taejun Kim, Heesuk Son, Dongman Lee Korea Computer Congress 2017

AWARDS

Best Master's Thesis Award, KAIST School of Computing

FAB. 2021

Thesis Title: "Improving Recognition Accuracy of Wrist-Worn Spatiotemporal Tactile Display using Heterogeneous Vibrotactile Stimuli"

EDUCATION

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science

SEP. 2020 – Present

Advisor: Geehyuk Lee, Ph.D.

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea

M.S. in Computer Science

2020

Thesis: "Improving Recognition Accuracy of Wrist-Worn Spatiotemporal Tactile Display using Heterogeneous Vibrotactile Stimuli"

Advisor: Geehyuk Lee, Ph.D.

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea

B.S. in Computer Science

2018

WORK Experience

Collaborative Distributed System & Networks Lab, KAIST

MAR. 2017 – JAN. 2018

Research Intern

- Constructing smart space for human activity recognizing system

TAEJUN KIM 1 Last update: December 7, 2021

Applied Physics Dept. Hong Kong Polytechnic University

Jun. 2016 – Aug. 2016

Research Intern

- Developing real-time data collecting system for space analytics

Bhaptics DEC. 2015 – FEB. 2016

Frontend coder

- Web interface development, Service page renewal

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Lecture on SPSS & R practice

Ост. 2021

in CS584 Human-Computer Interaction, School of Computing, KAIST

Teaching Assistant

CS550 Software Engineering, KAIST	Spring 2021
CS300 Introduction to Algorithms	Fall 2020
CS204 Discrete Mathematics	Spring 2019
CS230 System Programming	Spring 2018
CS101 Introduction to Programming	Fall 2017

TAEJUN KIM

2

Last update: December 7, 2021